nationalgridus.com 2019-12-05

# Privacy Policy | National Grid

We are firmly committed to protecting our customers’ privacy. The following Privacy Policy, together with our Terms and Conditions, outline our information-gathering and dissemination practices for any and all of our customers’ information, including but not limited to, the collection and dissemination of information from this website (“site”), our mobile application (“app”), our customer agreements and any other means by which you provide your information to National Grid. National Grid means National Grid USA Service Company Inc. and its United States affiliates.

By providing any information to us, and by accessing and using the site and/or app, you agree that you have read and understand this Privacy Policy and that you accept and consent to the privacy practices and uses or disclosures of information about you that are described herein. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not use the site and/or app or provide us with any personal information.

**Security**

We use SSL (or Secure Sockets Layer) as our primary form of security protection. A Secure Sockets Layer is a protocol that hides the information sent between the browser and server. An SSL-enhanced browser uses encryption to scramble the transferring data you send to a website into randomized characters for decoding. This is the industry standard for encrypting digital communications between any two points across a network.

Most browsers will illustrate that you are entering or leaving a secure area by presenting a dialog box. However, most browsers also give you the option of turning off the dialog box display.

When on a secure page, you will see the lock icon on the bottom of your Internet Explorer or Netscape web browser. Other browsers have different ways of displaying this information.

While we have put in place commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect from our customers, including the information we collect on our site and in our app, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure and therefore we cannot guarantee the security of any data sent to us electronically, and the transmission of such data is therefore entirely at your own risk.

**Information We Collect and Use of Your Information**

We use order forms which allow customers to request information and apply for services. When applicable, we collect personal contact information (such as your e-mail address and home address). This information is used to answer your questions, solve your problems, and provide interactivity. We do not provide this information to any other parties. Additionally, we may collect:

  * Details of your visits to our site or use of our app, and the resources that you access, including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, including your IP address, the date and time you accessed or left the site or app and which pages you viewed. Some parts of our site or app use cookies and other technologies to collect this information about your general Internet usage. See section below, ”How We Use Cookies,” to learn more.
  * Information that you provide directly to us, such as your customer agreements or other forms, including on our site or app (for example, to contact us through the site, you must provide your name and e-mail address).
  * Information provided to us when you communicate with us for any reason.

In addition to using this information to provide services to you, we may use this information to provide third parties with de-identified statistical information about the users of our site and app, and to monitor and conduct an analysis of our site and app traffic and usage patterns.

By submitting a telephone number to us you agree that a representative of National Grid can contact you at the number you provide, potentially using automated technology (including texts/SMS messaging) or a pre-recorded message. Your consent to telephone contact is not an obligation to receive any of our services.

**How We Use Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your device. We use session ID cookies and persistent cookies on our site and in our app. A session ID cookie is temporary. Once you close your browser, the cookie terminates. A persistent cookie is stored on a device’s hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser “help” file directions.

On our site and in our app, cookies are not used to invade the privacy of Internet users. We do not track our users across websites or across time.

Our cookies are used to improve the user experience. Persistent cookies enable us to track site and app usage patterns and analyze trends in the aggregate data reports. This helps us to make www.nationalgridus.com more useful to visitors. If users reject this cookie, they will continue to have full site and app access. This cookie does not include any personally identifiable information.

We also use cookies to create a continuous connection to the site and app. This type of cookie (a session ID cookie) is only temporary and allows users to complete a form.

We do not use flash cookies. Flash cookies are small pieces of information stored and accessed by Adobe Flash. 

**Disclosing your Information**

Because protecting your privacy is important to us, National Grid does not sell, trade, rent, give or distribute information about you to any third party. However, where applicable, we may disclose your personal information to any affiliated business entities to provide products and services to you.

We may also disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * Where we sell any or all of our business and/or our assets to a third party, whether through bankruptcy proceedings or other sale or merger.
  * Where we are legally required to disclose your information.
  * When we are contractually obligated to disclose your information. 

**Links to Third Party Websites**

Our site and app provide links to other pages on the Internet. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. When you leave our site or app, we encourage you to read the privacy statements of each website that collects personally identifiable information.

We also contract with vendors to provide enhanced customer information through the Internet. These third-party websites are not under the control of National Grid, and we are not responsible for their contents. These websites have separate privacy and data collection practices, independent of National Grid. We are not responsible or liable for these websites’ independent practices, policies or actions. If you provide any personal information while visiting these websites, you are solely responsible, and do so at your own risk.

**Children’s Privacy Policy**

“Educational support” is a section of www.nationalgridus.com that includes links to external websites containing information directed at educating children about energy use and safety. Please see the section above, “Links to Third Party Websites.”

www.nationalgridus.com will not collect information that would let us or anyone else contact or personally identify children under the age of 13.

www.nationalgridus.com will not use “cookies” to collect information for contact or identification purposes of children under the age of 13.

www.nationalgridus.com will not allow visitors to publicly post or otherwise send information that would let anyone contact or personally identify children who are under the age of 13.

www.nationalgridus.com will not promise special games, prizes or other offers as a way to try to get information from children under the age of 13 or to encourage children under the age of 13 to take part in activities on our site or in our app.

Under no circumstances shall children under the age of 13 submit personal information to our site or app. We are not liable for any damages that may result from a user’s misrepresentation of age.

**European Union  **

For personal information of individuals that National Grid receives from the European Union, National Grid has committed to handling such personal information in accordance with the

EU data protection laws.  For personal information transferred from the EU, National Grid utilizes the European Commission’s standard contractual clauses commonly known as “model clauses.”  These model clauses are contract templates developed by the European Commission as a mechanism for contracting parties to legalize the cross-border transfer of personal data from Europe.

Please note that the model clauses will apply to the extent there is not another legal basis in place to validate the transfer of personal data from the EU to the U.S.

To learn more about the EU’s model clauses, please visit <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/transfer/index_en.htm>.

National Grid has further committed to refer unresolved complaints regarding personal information of individuals that National Grid receives from the European Union to JAMS Mediation and Arbitrators (“JAMS”), an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact or visit [https://www.jamsadr.com](https://www.jamsadr.com/)  for more information or to file a complaint. The services of JAMS are provided at no cost to you.

**Disclaimer**

National Grid makes no guarantee, warranty or representation, express or implied (including implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose), with regard to the accuracy, completeness, usefulness, timeliness or suitability of the information being provided on our site or in our app.

It is expressly understood and agreed that neither National Grid nor its directors, officers, employees or agents shall assume any liability or responsibility for any damages or claims resulting from any use or disclosure of the information being provided on our site or in our app.

For more information regarding online privacy issues, please visit the Federal Trade Commission homepage at [http://www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/).

**Modifications to Privacy Policy**

We may modify this Privacy Policy at any time; please check back for updates. If we materially alter our Privacy Policy, we will notify you of such changes by posting a notice on our site or in the app, and/or by contacting you at the e-mail address provided to us. Providing information to us after implementation of our new policy, and/or your continued use of the site and app, will be deemed your agreement that your information may be used in accordance with the new policy. If you do not agree with the changes, then you should not provide additional information to us, stop using the site or app and you should notify us that you do not want your information used in accordance with the changes.

**Contacting Us**

We offer various ways that you may contact us online regarding queries, comments, requests or complaints—by e-mail or online forms. Please note that while we are in the process of answering your questions or fulfilling your request, information you submit to us may be seen by various people in National Grid. If you decide to send us personally identifying information—for example, in an e-mail containing a question or problem—we will only use this information to help us solve your problem or answer your question. If you have any questions about this privacy statement, please contact us.

National Grid  
Data Privacy  
175 East Old Country Rd  
Hicksville, New York 11801

**Effective Date:** May 18, 2018
